<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-05T18:24:08-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cidney.org</title><author><name>Cidney Hamilton</name></author><entry><title type="html">December Life Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/05/december-life-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="December Life Update" /><published>2021-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/05/december-life-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/05/december-life-update.html">&lt;p&gt;I have a wife now! Cat and I got handfasted in early November, at a nature preserve near where we live. Because of complicated family dynamics, we kept things very small. We’re planning a separate reception for our families in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still working on the VR port of &lt;a href=&quot;http://kensgame.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ken Williams’ new game&lt;/a&gt;. It’s actively moving along; check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://cygnusentertainment.com/blog/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ken’s blog&lt;/a&gt; for updates. I’m focused on user interface development right now and working closely with Roberta Williams; things are coming along nicely, and I can’t wait for people to be able to play it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ken recently started a new company– Cygnus Entertainment– and hired two technical artists and one programmer, all of whom have been helping out with my project. I’d been working seven day weeks and getting very stressed out, so it’s good to have more help and be able to take weekends off without needing to provide technical support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife has taken over the house tabletop game. I’d decided to adapt an old Gary Gygax module for my group (Cat and our roommate, Nick), and got them through Gary Gygax’s The Village of Hommlet, first published in 1979, ported to my homebrew campaign setting. Cat is now having us playtest a module she’s written for the same campaign setting, based on Mussorgsky (and Walt Disney’s) Night on Bald Mountain. I’m playing a Serbian Jew and self-taught wizard living in Belgrade in 999, currently on a mission to investigate a haunting in a local village, but knowing Cat can expect things to progress into something more apocalyptic soon. We have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://campaignwiki.org/wiki/NightOnBaldMountain/HomePage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;campaign wiki&lt;/a&gt; I’m trying to keep up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was optimistically hoping to do another draft of my novel for NaNoWriMo, but have had zero time. I’m focusing aggressively on tying up loose ends and getting my life in order, so I can make the most of nights and weekends and have time to finish the book. Getting some downtime has been good; but going back to it has been discouraging (“wait, I &lt;em&gt;wrote&lt;/em&gt; this? this is terrible!”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made it to EmacsConf last weekend, which was a lot of fun. In college we had to do our problem sets in emacs, but once I graduated I ended up using the IDEs everyone else was using at work to reduce friction (I had a BA in computer science from a liberal arts college, and considered myself lucky to get an engineering job at all!). I ended up switching back to emacs a couple years ago to finish my novel; it takes &lt;a href=&quot;https://elizadev.medium.com/using-unity-editor-with-emacs-9316eb441411&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; some fiddling&lt;/a&gt; to get it usable in Unity, but is well worth it. I still have a LOT to learn, though, and often feel daunted by how different my background is than most people’s!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cidney Hamilton</name></author><summary type="html">I have a wife now! Cat and I got handfasted in early November, at a nature preserve near where we live. Because of complicated family dynamics, we kept things very small. We’re planning a separate reception for our families in the near future.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Emitting More Light</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/26/emitting-more-light.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Emitting More Light" /><published>2021-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/26/emitting-more-light</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/10/26/emitting-more-light.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been years since I posted something personal on my website. I wasn’t always this withdrawn. In my teens, I kept a public personal blog. I wasn’t afraid to express emotion, or to embarrass myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I stopped. My personal website became a business card; a place for people to get in touch with me, and to hold onto a domain name I had no active use for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was scared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was scared that if I had a platform, I would say the wrong things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had chronic depression as a teen and young adult. By the time I was ten years old, I began dwelling seriously on suicide as the only way to escape a truly awful home environment, and made a serious suicide attempt at 21. I had become overwhelmed and hopeless about the pressures of supporting myself and/or affording an undergraduate degree in the recession without support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My life became better after I got my university degree and proved I could support myself. But I still struggle with chronic suicidal ideation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s background noise at this point, but it’s become a habit that I still fall back to in times of stress; when I have a bad enough setback, suicide is always one of the first options that come to mind. This how my brain is wired now. It’s part of how I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any kind of suicidal ideation can be taken out of context and seen as a threat, by both good and bad actors. So I’ve stayed silent, to avoid things coming up to hurt or haunt me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But keeping secrets comes at a cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m told I’m hard to get to know. I’m frequently silent. I often feel fake; in interactions with colleagues, even with people who claim me as a friend. I wear masks, and they become quiet heavy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem is, if I stay silent, everyone else who is struggling and stays silent will think they’re alone. I’ve lost one good friend to suicide, and several acquaintances that should not have died so young. I had no idea that any of them were suicidal until after they were dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had, could I have talked to them about it? Helped them feel less alone? (Having suicidal thoughts is often a source of shame; you’re weak, you’re dysfunctional, you’re crazy.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll never know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I want to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s safer to stay silent. It’s easy to keep my head down and present the Spock-like facade of a hyper-confident programmer, all logic and no emotions. But it’s not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m going to start talking more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I’m not alone here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it’s selfish to hold back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I want to emit more light.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cidney Hamilton</name></author><summary type="html">It’s been years since I posted something personal on my website. I wasn’t always this withdrawn. In my teens, I kept a public personal blog. I wasn’t afraid to express emotion, or to embarrass myself.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">September Life Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/25/september-life-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="September Life Update" /><published>2021-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/09/25/september-life-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/09/25/september-life-update.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m still in Florida! I’ve been in Florida for five years now. I’m getting handfasted to my fiancee in October, then trying to wrap things up and move in the spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://kensgame.com&quot;&gt;a new adventure game&lt;/a&gt; right now, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sierragamers.com/&quot;&gt;Ken and Roberta Williams&lt;/a&gt;, of Sierra Online! I’m primarily working on the VR port (which meant I had to get a VR headset and learn how to develop for it), but getting my hands dirty with all sorts of things. The game is still top secret, but will hopefully be able to share more about it as it gets further to release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my first full-time job since getting diagnosed with Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome back in 2015. Around that time, I had crippling back and joint pain after leaving the office, and was struggling to hack it. The EDS diagnosis helped me figure out what was causing the pain, but shortly afterwards, I had lots of setbacks… a bad car accident where I broke my spine (and couldn’t walk for a year), a botched spinal fusion, and a bout of MRSA. I’ve managed to recover and am more functional now than I ever felt possible… although I need to spend several hours a day on physical therapy, and have to be very careful to protect my joints and avoid further injury. I was working part-time for the Coles (other Sierra alums) before this started, who were heroically supportive, but as my health improved and my medical bills ate up my savings from working in tech, I both needed and wanted more work. Ken is a notoriously demanding boss, but so far it’s been a good fit; I enjoy being challenged and I’m learning a lot from working with them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still revising my novel, although it’s going much more slowly now on top of game development. My goal was to write a southern gothic set around the area I grew up, and being in Florida has allowed me to do a great deal of research… but this is my first completed book, and I worry a lot that I’ve bit off more than I can chew with some of the literary themes. I’ve written three drafts at this point, and I’m guessing I’ll go through a dozen before I consider it “good enough”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pandemic has been taking its toll. I got vaccinated in April, but had a bad reaction to my first dose, and was in and out of the hospital for about a month. Most of my friends with EDS have gotten long COVID, where they were incapacitated from the beginning of the pandemic until their first dose of vaccine, so overall, I’ve been lucky. I miss my friends up north; I miss the other narrative game developers I’ve been starting to connect with; and I worry a lot about the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cidney Hamilton</name></author><summary type="html">I’m still in Florida! I’ve been in Florida for five years now. I’m getting handfasted to my fiancee in October, then trying to wrap things up and move in the spring.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">January 2021 Life Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/01/15/january-life-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="January 2021 Life Update" /><published>2021-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/01/15/january-life-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/01/15/january-life-update.html">&lt;p&gt;Before the pandemic, I was planning on leaving Florida. I’m likely to be here for some time now, though. So far, I haven’t gotten sick, but many people I care about have. The world is a frightening place these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m continuing to revise my novel. I have a complete draft, but there’s a lot of work left to get it to be as polished as I would like it to be. I’m finished with the part where I have to work on it extensively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been migrating to a mostly self-hosted setup, for code, files, and social media. I’m beginning to work on figuring out what I’m comfortable sharing and not sharing, and what to include on this website.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cidney Hamilton</name></author><summary type="html">Before the pandemic, I was planning on leaving Florida. I’m likely to be here for some time now, though. So far, I haven’t gotten sick, but many people I care about have. The world is a frightening place these days.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Facebook and the Steady Erosion of User Privacy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/15/facebook-and-the-steady-erosion-of-user-privacy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Facebook and the Steady Erosion of User Privacy" /><published>2019-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/15/facebook-and-the-steady-erosion-of-user-privacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/15/facebook-and-the-steady-erosion-of-user-privacy.html">&lt;p&gt;The summer before I started college, I logged into my brand new dot-edu email account. From there, I got invited to join a website called “the facebook”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thefacebook, in 2004.The Facebook, at the time, was just an “online directory that connects people through social networks at colleges”. There was no newsfeed; groups were a joke; and in order to send instant messages, you still needed to use AIM or ICQ. All Facebook had was a collection of profiles. There were about two dozen colleges on the network; expanding from just Harvard in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The year was 2004. I was sixteen years old and a high school graduate; the product of skipping fourth grade and having a late birthday. I’d been admitted to Wellesley College, a small liberal arts school just outside of Boston. I was a socially awkward computer geek with the faintest trace of a Southern accent. Nobody I went to college with had even heard of the town I’d grown up in. I had no idea how to make friends in a new environment; especially given how much younger I was than all my peers. When it came to social networking, I needed all the help I could get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created an account. I had a couple acquaintances on Facebook, but all of my close friends were staying in state for college, and the only school in Florida that was “on Facebook” at the time was the University of Florida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, it wasn’t hard to make Facebook friends. My classmates would send me friend requests; so would the people in my dorm. Facebook wasn’t a dating site (the dating site equivalent was the equally sketchy MIT Matchup, where Boston college students could match with equally pedigreed Boston college students).
I accepted a friend request from Jesus, and I sent a friend request to Satan. I joined silly groups. When I cross-registered at MIT and Harvard, I made Facebook profiles with my new email addresses, so that the Cidney Hamilton from Wellesley could be in a relationship with the Cidney Hamilton from MIT.
It got boring quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember what I was saying about the news feed? Without that, in order to find out what people were up to, you had to stalk them directly. That felt invasive and weird. I had other, better means of maintaining contact with real life and online friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, because I was so young, I didn’t go to parties or get drunk, and Facebook seemed to mostly be people posting pictures of themselves getting drunk at parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it was a stupid website built by a stupid kid my age who went to school nearby. I didn’t take it seriously. Nobody else did. It was just a procrastination tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, it started becoming mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2005, high school students started joining Facebook. More colleges were on Facebook. At first it seemed a little weird (since, you know, we shouldn’t be talking about “looking for random play” in front of high school kids), but it made it much easier for me to stay in touch with friends a few grades younger than me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the corporations and nonprofits showed up. Graduating seniors could stay on Facebook. You could now join a corporate social network instead of a college one; and you didn’t need a dot-edu email address to create an account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was… a bit more worrisome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was Facebook going to do next? Invite our parents?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, in 2006, Facebook made the decision to allow everyone with an email address to sign up for an account. You didn’t have to be in school any more. The core user base of college students was no longer the target audience; everyone else wanted to be on Facebook, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not okay with this. Lots of original users were not okay with this. There were protest groups on Facebook. But Facebook still opened up to the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing was, people had already posted these embarrassing pictures of themselves, thinking that nobody besides their peers were ever going to see them. Ten years later, these embarrassing pictures are routinely dug up to slut-shame Millennials who run for office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened to Krystal Ball in 2010. It happened in my local city council race last year. It’s happening to Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez now (with limited success). The drunk selfies everyone posted to Facebook when it was just an ephemeral toy can now be posted as evidence of someone’s “true nature”: if either you’re a thug, or a whore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this is coming to light now. But the seeds of Facebook’s lack of concern about the privacy of its users have been there for over a dozen years.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cidney Hamilton</name></author><summary type="html">The summer before I started college, I logged into my brand new dot-edu email account. From there, I got invited to join a website called “the facebook”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello, World!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/01/test-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, World!" /><published>2019-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/01/test-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/01/test-post.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m not actually blogging yet. I’m just creating a test post to see if it’s possible to blog in the future. More on this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Cidney Hamilton</name></author><summary type="html">I’m not actually blogging yet. I’m just creating a test post to see if it’s possible to blog in the future. More on this in the future.</summary></entry></feed>